# Elizabeth Yalkut

I'm here to make the internet better: more accessible, tidier, and easier to navigate. I create the user experience with CSS, HTML, and JavaScript. I'm a front-end developer dedicated to making the internet gorgeous, accessible, and useful. My job is to make information available and easy to understand, and I'm good at it. I believe in collaboration, code review, and creative solutions.

**Email**: ey@elizabethyalkut.com **Phone**: 718-395-7310

Website: elizabethyalkut.com

# Skills and Knowledge

I write concise CSS and SASS that takes advantage of developing specifications and progressively enhances the user experience. My HTML is semantic, accessible, and modular, putting content first. I know vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, and Angular. I've worked with Wordpress, Drupal, and Django as CMSes, am comfortable with git and svn, and can conduct user tests and implement analytics strategies. I've worked in Agile teams, can turn a Photoshop image of a web site into a working site, and I document and test as I go.

# **Experience**

#### Web Developer

Databases & Web Initiatives, Office of Alumni and Development, Columbia University July 2012 - present

The Databases & Web Initiatives team at the Office of Alumni and Development of Columbia University is responsible for maintenance and development of the donor database, as well as internal and external websites and applications.

#### Responsibilities

- Design, maintain and develop Drupal, Wordpress and other sites written in PHP, JavaScript (jQuery and jQueryui), HTML/CSS
- Produce technical outcomes based on user stories defined for one-week sprint cycles
- Embrace emerging standards while promoting best practices
- Partner with and train fellow team members, marketing, communication and CAA staff on CMS and HTML/CSS
- Work well both independently and as part of a team

**Key projects**: redesign the online giving forms for Columbia University; relaunch of the internal Human Resources Planning & Performance Tool for Office of Alumni and Development (new design and user testing); lead development of CAA Arts Access website.

### **Front-End Developer**

Threespot Media October 2011 - June 2012

Threespot is an independent digital engagement agency that crafts experiences and connections between brands and consumers.

#### **Developer**

Do Something June 2011 - September 2011

Do Something is a New York City notfor-profit dedicated to activating young people in their communities.

#### **Computing Fellow**

Barnard College Educational Technology September 2008 - May 2011

Computing Fellows at Barnard College Educational Technology help faculty and staff integrate technology into their teaching and learning.

### Responsibilities

- Served as front-end lead on relaunch of MacArthur Foundation website
- Created CSS and HTML for relaunch of Brookings Institute website, as part of a five-person team

### Responsibilities

- Conducted A/B testing to improve user conversion rates
- Created individually branded microsites for campaigns

### Responsibilities

- Created podcasts introducing Internet law, social media, and user-generated content
- Updated social media accounts, including Facebook and Twitter
- Supported faculty and staff in use of software, including Office and Dreamweaver
- Created, updated, and maintained PHP-based websites for academic departments

# **Education**

Barnard College, Columbia University, Bachelor of Arts, History, May 2011 Courses include: Statistics, Research Seminar in History, Public Speaking

Emma Willard School, Diploma, June 2004

## **Awards and Nominations**

2014 Best of the Net

Nominated by the Editors of Spry.

Tow Research Fellowship

Barnard College, 2010

Awarded to support senior thesis

research.

Bertha Vapnek Research Fellowship

Barnard College, 2010

Awarded to support senior thesis
research.

Bregman Computing Fellowship
Barnard College, 2009-2011
Awarded for ability to assist
faculty and staff with technology

Elizabeth Hughes Gossett Scholarship Barnard College, 2008-2009 Awarded to a student with demonstrated leadership skills and interest in public service

# **Training**

- Google Analytics training 201 and 301, Luna Metrics, November 2014
- UX Certification, Nielsen Norman Group, September 2014
- SmashingConf, June 2014 (Workshops: SMACSS: Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS; Real-Life Responsive Web Design)
- Presenting Data and Information, Edward Tufte, October 2013
- Negotiating to Win, American Management Association, April 2013